You're only as strong as your next move.
Begin Again is a comedy, music, romance film directed by John Carney.
Gretta, a budding songwriter, finds herself alone
after her boyfriend Dave ditches her.
Her life gains purpose when Dan, a record label executive, notices her talent.
Dan Mulligan, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Gretta James, played by Keira Knightley.
Dave Kohl, played by Adam Levine.
Violet Mulligan, played by Hailee Steinfeld.
Miriam Hart, played by Catherine Keener.
Steve, played by James Corden.
Begin Again is a 2013 American musical comedy-drama film written and directed
by John Carney, and starring Keira Knightley and Mark Ruffalo.
Knightley plays a singer-songwriter who is discovered by a struggling record label executive (Ruffalo) and
collaborates with him to produce an album recorded in public locations all over New York City.
After the success of his 2007 musical film Once, Carney wrote the script in 2010
and employed Gregg Alexander to compose most of the film's music.
With a US$8 million budget, production began in July 2012 with filming
taking place in various locations around New York City.
The film premiered under its original title Can a Song Save Your Life?
at the 2013 Toronto International Film Festival, and was released theatrically on June
27, 2014, in conjunction with the release of the film's soundtrack.
It has grossed $63.4 million worldwide and received
mostly positive reviews from critics.
It was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Original Song for "Lost Stars".
The film explores themes of new york city, music recording,
singer-songwriter, street musician, city life.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.